Guide to the Church League of America Collection of the Research Files of Counterattack, the Wackenhut Corporation, and Karl Baarslag TAM.148
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Wackenhut Corporation Research Files, 1931-1973; 1955-1973
  - Deacons for Defense and Justice (9-133), 1965 (Box 34, Folder 55)
  - Newsletter (Southern Student Organizing Committee) (9-134), 1960s (Box 34, Folder 56)
  - Daedalus (9-135), 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 57)
  - Humanist (9-137), 1966-1968 (Box 34, Folder 58)
  - New York Review of Books (9-137), 1966 (Box 34, Folder 59)
  - Atlas (9-138), 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 60)
  - Jewish Daily News (9-139), 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 61)
  - Communist Viewpoint (9-140), 1966-1969 (Box 34, Folder 62)
  - Reverend Philip Berrigan, et al (The Harrisburg Seven) (9-141), 1970-1972 (Box 34, Folder 63-64)
  - Reverend Philip Berrigan, et al (The Harrisburg Seven) (9-141), 1970-1972 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Peace-Keeping Ways and Means Committee, Inc. (9-142), 1966 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - "A Portrait of China" (9-143), 1971 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Currents (9-144), 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Embassy of the USSR (9-145), 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Organization to Abolish Federal Income Tax (9-146), 1966 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - The Guild Practitioner (9-147), 1966-1968 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Manchester Guardian (9-148), 1966 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - New York Independent (9-149), 1966 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - The Independent (9-151), 1966 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Studies on the Left (9-152), 1965-1968 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - K. Baarslag File (A) [Acheson, Adamic, Anderson, etc.] (9-154-173), 1944-1965 (Box 35, Folder 12-13)
  - K. Baarslag File (A-B) [Ashmore, Ascoli, Arnautoff, Armstrong, etc.] (9-174-195), 1943-1956 (Box 35, Folder 14-15)
  - K. Baarslag File (B) [Baldwin, Budenz, Bovingdon, Bush, Bridges, Belafonte, Baker, Bruce, Betancourt, etc.] (9-196-270), 1943-1965 (Box 35, Folder 16-17)
  - K. Baarslag File (B) [Benton, Bentley, Bennett, Bella, Beck, Rustin, Barth, Barnett, Bang-Jensen, Ball, etc.] (9-271-286), 1953-1968 (Box 35, Folder 18-20)
  - K. Baarslag File (B) [Braden, Bohlen, Blake, Betancourt, Bosch, Bofman, Bodde, Blair, Bibb, Bernstein] (9-287-297), 1954-1964 (Box 35, Folder 21-22)
  - K. Baarslag File (Browder, Earl) (9-298), 1942-1966 (Box 35, Folder 23-24)
  - K. Baarslag File (B) [Burck, Burke, Bunche, Buchanan, Buck, Bryan, etc.] (9-299-309), 1931-1964 (Box 35, Folder 25-27)
  - K. Baarslag File (C) [Clay, Case, Carter, Casals, Chambers, etc.] (9-310-370), 1950s-1960s (Box 35, Folder 28-30)
  - K. Baarslag File (C) [Cohen, Coe, Clubb, Cleveland, Church, Chisholm,Childs, Chaplin, Clement, etc.] (9-371-383), 1950s-1960s (Box 35, Folder 31-32)
  - K. Baarslag File (C) [Conant, Commager, Cohen, Cohn, etc.] (9-384-387), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - K. Baarslag File (C) [Crosby, Crankshaw, Crane, Cousins, Cranston, Cordier, Corbin, Coplon, Copland, Cooke, Cook, Condon, Chamberlain] (9-388-401), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 3-5)
  - K. Baarslag File (H) [Hughes, Humphrey, Horton, Horsky, Hook, Hoover] (9-685-690), 1940s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 6-8)
  - K. Baarslag File (H-J) [Jack, Jones, Jouncey, Johnson, Jackson, Johnston, Jessup, Jordan, Jacobs, Imes, Isaacs, Ivens, Isserman, Innerst, Hutchins, etc.] (9-691-727), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 9-10)
  - K. Baarslag File (K) [Kunstler, Karr, Kamp, Kern, Knowles, etc.] (9-728-771), 1950s-1970s (Box 36, Folder 11-12)
  - K. Baarslag (K) [Kirsch, Klineberg, Kuchel, etc.] (9-772-777), 1960s (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Reverend Doctor Martin Luther King, Jr. (9-778 I), 1960s (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Reverend Doctor Martin Luther King, Jr. (9-778 II), 1960s (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - K. Baarslag File (K) [Kent, Kestnbaum, Killian, King] (9-779-783), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - K. Baarslag File (L) [Lamont, Ladejinsky, Lamb, etc.] (9-784-833), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 17-18)
  - K. Baarslag File (L) [Lattimore, Larson, Lancaster, Landis, etc.] (9-834-840), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 19-21)
  - K. Baarslag File (L) [Lynd, Lynch, Lowenthal, Lovett, Lloyd, Littel, Lindeman, Lindley, Lincoln, Levy, Lerner, etc.] (9-841-859), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 22-23)
  - K. Baarslag File (M) (9-860-956), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 24-26)
  - K. Baarslag File (M) [Matusow, Matthews, Martin, Mallon, Malcolm X, MacLennan, MacLeish, etc.] (9-957-969), 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 27-28)
  - K. Baarslag File (M) [Matusow, Matthews, Martin, Mallon, Malcolm X, MacLennan, MacLeish, etc.] (9-957-969), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - K. Baarslag File (Kissinger, Henry) (9-970), 1962-1972 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - K. Baarslag File (M) [Melish, Mead, Meacham, Mazey, Mays, Mayer, Marzani, Marshall] (9-971-980), 1940s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 3-5)
  - K. Baarslag File (M) [Miller, Milestone, Meyer, Menoyo, Menon, Melman] (9-981-988), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - K. Baarslag File (M) [Muste, Myrdal, Murray, Muelder, Mowrer, Morse, Morrison, Morris, Morgenthau, Moore, Montagu, Mitford, Miller] (9-989-1009), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 7-9)
  - K. Baarslag File (N) [Nulsen, Norman, Nkrumah, Nixon, Nitze, Niles, Niebuhr, Nearing, Neal, Natvig, Nelson, Neuberger, Niemeyer, etc.] (9-1010-1034), 1960s (Box 37, Folder 10-11)
  - K. Baarslag File (O) [Oliver, O'Connor, O'Brien, O'Neill, Odegard, Ost, Odell, Odets, Orloff, Owens, Oppenheimer, Oswald] (9-1035-1049), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 12-14)
  - K. Baarslag File (O) [Oxnam, Overstreet] (9-1050-1051), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 15-16)
  - K. Baarslag File (P) [Poitier, Peter Paul and Mary, Paar, Peffer, Price, Packard, Parlin, Peabody, Pauling, etc.] (9-1052-1079), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 17-18)
  - K. Baarslag File (P) [Pearson, Parker, Paton, Papirofsky, Papp] (9-1080-1084), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 19-21)
  - K. Baarslag File (P) [Petersen, Peters, Peterson, Perlo, Pegler, Pearson] (9-1085-1090), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - K. Baarslag File (Philbrick, Herbert) (9-1091), 1960s-1970s (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - K. Baarslag File (P) [Powell, Porter, Pope, Polowsky, Poe, Pike, Pickett, Picasso] (9-1092-1100), 1948-1967 (Box 37, Folder 24-25)
  - K. Baarslag File (P) [Pusey, Proxmire, Preminger, Powell, Poynter] (9-1101-1105), 1950s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - K. Baarslag File (Q - R) [Quill, Resnick, Ray, Rembar, Riley, Robeson, Rosen, Rose, Rice, Robinson, Rorty, Roy, Rafferty, Randolph, Raugh, Rauh, Redmont, Ray, Reed, Refregier, etc.] (9-1106-1168), 1930s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - K. Baarslag File (Q - R) [Quill, Resnick, Ray, Rembar, Riley, Robeson, Rosen, Rose, Rice, Robinson, Rorty, Roy, Rafferty, Randolph, Raugh, Rauh, Redmont, Ray, Reed, Refregier, etc.] (9-1106-1168), 1930s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
  - K. Baarslag File (Marcus G. Raskin) (9-1123), 1960-1970 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - K. Baarslag File (R) [Robeson, Rivera, Ritt, Rickett, Richardson, Reynolds, Reuther, Reston, Redding, Reissig, Reischauer] (9-1169-1179), 1940s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 4-6)
  - K. Baarslag File (R) [Roosevelt, Rogge, Rogers, Rockwell, Rockefeller, Roberts, Roche, Robinson] (9-1180-1190), 1930s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 7-9)
  - K. Baarslag File (R) [Rustin, Russell, Rusk, Rubin, Rorty, Rayburn, Roy, Rowan, Rovere, Rossiter, Rosenberg, Roosevelt] (9-1190-1202), 1950s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 10-11)
  - K. Baarslag File (S) [Salisbury, Salinger, Straight, Sutcliffe, Simpson, Schechter, Steuben, Stone, Scalpino, Sinatra, Schwartz, etc.] (9-1203-1263), 1950s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 12-13)
  - K. Baarslag File (S) [Service, Sentner, Segal, Schweitser, Schuman, Schreiber, Schary, Schwartz, Schlesinger, Scales, Savio, Sandburg, etc.] (9-1264-1278), 1950s-1960s (Box 38, Folder 14-16)
  - [K. Baarslag File] [Stern, Steel, Stassen, Spock, Soule, Sorenson, Solomon] (9-1293-1299), 1949-1964 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Pete Seeger (9-1275), 1961-1971 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - John Kerry (9-1293), 1971-1972 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Daniel Ellsberg (9-1294), undated (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Jewish Defense League/Meir Kahane (9-1295), 1971-1972 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Dr. Benjamin Spock (9-1296), 1965-1972 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Soviet Intelligence (R. Michaelowski) (9-1297), 1961-1971 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Vietnam Veterans Against the War (VVAW) (9-1299), 1972 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Communism - General Clippings - China, USSR (9-1300a), 1972 (Box 38, Folder 25-27)
  - Communism - General Clippings - China, USSR (9-1300b), 1972-1973 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Our Sunday Visitor (9-1301), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Socialist Workers Party (9-1302), 1966-1972 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Patriotic Party (Minutemen organization) (9-1303), 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - New Pioneer (9-1304), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - Commentary (9-1305), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - Dissent (9-1306), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - Herbert Aptheker (9-1307), 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - Success (9-1308), 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - Despite Everything (9-1309), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - Commonweal (9-1310), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - American Mercury (9-1311), 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - Idea Catalyst (9-1312), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - Jane Fonda (9-1313), 1972 (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - Conference of Socialist Scholars (9-1314), 1965-1967 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - American Indian affairs (9-1315), 1972 (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) (9-1316), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) (9-1316), 1965-1972 (Box 39, Folder 3-5)
  - War Resisters League (9-1317), 1963-1967 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - New School for Social Research (9-1318), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Glenn W. Turner (9-1318), 1972 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - People's Party (9-1320), 1972 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - The Reuther Memorandum (9-1321), 1964 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Radical Education Project (SDS) (9-1322), 1966-1967 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Labor News and Views (9-1323), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Global Views (9-1324), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - National Conference for New Politics (9-1325), 1966-1967 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Staughton Lynd (9-1326), 1965 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Eugene Genovese (9-1327), 1965-1966 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Bettina Aptheker (9-1328), 1965-1967 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - United Farm Workers Union (9-1329), 1972 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Catalyst (9-1330), 1966-1969 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - University Bookman (9-1331), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Berkeley Riots (Berkeley, Calif.) (9-1332), 1965-1967 (Box 39, Folder 21-22)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation (9-1333), 1966-1967 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - The Peacemaker (9-1334), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Our Generation (9-1335), 1966-1968 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Alternatives (9-1336), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - CARIB (Caribbean Anti-Communist Research Intelligence Bureau) (9-1337), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - MANAS (9-1338), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Communist Affairs (9-1339), 1966-1968 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Freedom and Anarchy (9-1340), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Anarchy (9-1340), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Labor Today (9-1343), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - N.Y. Federation of Anarchists (9-1344), Circa 1965 (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Viewpoint (Florida League for Good Government), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - American Atheist from Free Thought Society of America (9-1346), 1966-1967 (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - War/Peace Report (9-1347), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - Florida Folk Foundation (9-1348), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - Protective Bulletin (9-1349), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - The Activist (9-1350), 1967-1969 (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - Committee of 100 in Support of NAACP Legal Defense & Educational Fund (9-1351), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 40)
  - Sing Out! (9-1352), 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 41)
  - The Independent (Miami) (9-1353), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 42)
  - Ad-Hoc Bulletin (Marxist-Leninist) (9-1354), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 43)
  - Mothers of Servicemen Publications (9-1355), 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 44)
  - Women Strike for Peace (9-1356), 1962-1967 (Box 39, Folder 45)
  - Stokely Carmichael (Main File) (9-1357), 1966-1971 (Box 39, Folder 46-47)
  - Tri-Continental Conference [Havana, 1966] (9-1358), 1966-1967 (Box 39, Folder 48-50)
  - Organization for Latin American Security (9-1358A, serials 1A-135), 1966-1967 (Box 39, Folder 51-52)
  - Organization for Latin American Security (9-1358B, serials 136-246), 1967 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Organization for Latin American Security (9-1358A, serials 247-278), 1967-1969 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Cuba - Cultural Congress (9-1358B, serials 1-25), 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Reverend Carl McIntyre (9-1359), 1971 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Tampa Riots (9-1360), 1967 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - SLAM Newsletter (Southern Labor Action Movement) (9-1361), 1967 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Black Power (Main File) (9-1362), 1966-1968 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Daily World (9-1363), 1968-1969 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Revolutionary Action Movement (RAM) (9-1364), 1967-1969 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Adam Clayton Powell (9-1365), 1964-1971 (Box 40, Folder 11-12)
  - Joan Baez (9-1366), 1964-1971 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - H. Rap Brown (9-1367), 1967-1971 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Dick Gregory (9-1368), 1963-1969 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - James Meredith (9-1369), 1962-1968 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - [K. Baarslag File] (S)[Struik, Strong, Stokes, Strelsin, Stouffer, Stevenson] (9-1400-1406), 1951-1962 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - [K. Baarslag File] (S - T) [Thomas, Taylor, Thayer, Taylor, Taber, Trueblood, Trowbridge, Thurber, Tiffany, Trumbo, Templin, Timerman, Tippett, Trimble, Schary, Szulc, Symington, Sylvester, Sullivan, Strausz-Hope, Stuart, etc.] (9-1407-1437), undated (Box 40, Folder 18-20)
  - K. Baarslag File (T - V) [Tobias, Toon, Truman, Tunan, Tillich, Thompson, Toynbee, Twardy, Ulman, Urey, Uphal, U Thant, Vincent, Van Dusen, Van Kirk, Vidal, Vieg, Voorhis, Vivian] (9-1438-1509), 1943-1964 (Box 40, Folder 21-22)
  - K. Baarslag File (V - W) [White, Walsh, Winter, Wallach, Wallace, Wicker, Warren, Williams, Weinberg, Wilson, Walton, Wadleigh, Walker, Walls, Warburg] (9-1510-1523), 1948-1965 (Box 40, Folder 23-24)
  - K. Baarslag File (W) [Wenner, Warren, Wilkins, Ward, Weltfish, Watkins, Warren, Washburne, Waterman, Weaver, Wechsler, Wells, Walker] (9-1524-1537), 1953-1966 (Box 40, Folder 25-26)
  - K. Baarslag File (W) [Worthy, Wilcox, Welles, Wanamaker, Walton, Williams, Wiesner, Wyker, Wriston, Wright, Worthy, Withers, Wirt, Winston, Wilson, Wilkerson, Wieland, White, Westin, etc.] (9-1538-1571), 1953-1966 (Box 40, Folder 27-29)
  - K. Baarslag File (W) [Harry Dexter White, Woltman, Winston, Wick, Walton, Williams, Worley, Wanamaker, Wirin, Wilson, etc.] (9-1572-1599), 1943-1963 (Box 40, Folder 30-31)
  - K. Baarslag File (X - Z) [Zanuck, Zellerbach, Zborowski, Young, Zwicker, Yarmolinsky, Zuber, Yellin, Yorty, etc.] (9-1600-1620), 1956-1966 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Puerto Rico [Comandos Armados de Liberacion] (9-1621), 1968 (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - Youth International Party (Yippies) (9-1622), 1968-1969 (Box 40, Folder 34)
- Series III: Karl Baarslag Research Files, 1930-1968
  This series contains research files collected by Karl Baarslag, primarily between the 1930s and the mid-1960s, on organizations and issues he was monitoring for his work as a consultant and government employee. The files include materials collected on and from a wide variety of organizations, including nongovernmental, faith-based, civil rights and foreign policy organizations, trade unions, foundations, governmental agencies, news organizations, journals, anti-communist and right-wing organizations, and far right-wing organizations.
  The files include organizational newsletters, brochures, annual reports and circulars, apparently collected by Baarslag through subscriptions. There are also government publications, newspaper, magazine and journal clippings, anonymously authored confidential reports and typed profiles on organizations, and a relatively small amount of correspondence. Some files contain research materials apparently collected by Baarslag in the early 1950s during his tenure as research assistant for Senator Joseph McCarthy's Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations.
  Karl Herman William Baarslag was an author and professional anti-communist who served as research director under Senator Joseph McCarthy between July 1953 and 1954 for the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, and as a consultant for the House Committee on Un-American Activities beginning in 1956. Prior to joining McCarthy's subcommittee, Baarslag was Research Director for the National Americanism Commission of the American Legion, an anti-communist organization, and edited their newsletter, Firing Line.
  During World War II, Baarslag served in the anti-subversive branch of the Office of Naval Intelligence. Beginning in 1935, Baarslag was author of several books, as well as numerous anti-communist articles and pamphlets, some of which were published in Esquire and The American Mercury. Around 1959, Baarslag began to work for the Church League of America as its Chief of Research, and the Church League also published Baarslag's anti-communist textbook, Manual for Survival: A Counter-subversive Study Course.
  - AAC Book List, 1944, 1960-1961 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Action Books, 1959-1960 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Advance Youth Organization, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - African American Institute, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - African Fair Inc., 1960 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Afro-Asian Conference [All-African People's Conference], 1958-1959 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - All Russian Liberation Committee, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Amerasia [The Amerasia Case], 1946-1950 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - American Assembly, 1957-1965 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - American Association for the United Nations, Inc., 1955-1963 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1949-1964 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - American Association of University Women, 1955-1962 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - American Bar Association [Special Committee on Communist Tactics, Strategy and Onjectives], 1951-1964 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - American Bar Association - Syllabus ("Democracy and Communism in World Affairs") [Standing Committee on Education Against Communism], 1963 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - American Broadcasting Company (ABC) -- Alger Hiss Broadcast [Che Guevara Broadcast], 1962-1964 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - American Christian Palestine Committee, 1954-1958 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, Circa 1924-1968 (Box 41, Folder 18-19)
  - American Coalition of Patriotic Societies, Inc., May 1963 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - American Committee for Aid to Katanga Freedom Fighters, Dec 1961 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1956-1957 (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - American Committee for Liberation [Voice of America], Jun 13, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born [Miss Pettibone Smith], 1955-1960 (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - American Committee on Africa, circa 1959-1963 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - American Committee to Free Cuba, 1962-1963 (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - American Committee to Improve our Neighborhood (Action, Inc.) [National Council, Protestant Episcopal Church], 1955-1960 (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - American Communications Association, circa 1957 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1955-1959 (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - American Council of Christian Churches ["Why You Can't Build Churches: The Hand Over the Churches"], circa 1959 (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - American Council of Voluntary Agencies, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - American Council on Education, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1952-1960 (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - American Federation of Radio and Television Artists (AFTRA), 1952-1957 (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - American Field Service, 1954-1960 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - American Forum for Socialist Education, 1956-1957 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - American Freedom from Hunger Foundation, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - American Freedom of Residence Fund, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - American Friends of Russian Freedom, Circa 1955 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - American Friends Service Committee, Circa 1935-1965 (Box 41, Folder 40-42)
  - American Fund for Public Service, 1931-1934 (Box 41, Folder 43)
  - American Heritage Foundation, Circa 1950s (Box 41, Folder 44)
  - American Institute of Religion, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 45)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1962-1965 (Box 41, Folder 46)
  - American League Against War and Fascism, 1938-1939 (Box 41, Folder 47)
  - American Library Association - Bookburning; Blackout [James Rorty], 1955-1964 (Box 41, Folder 48)
  - American Nazi Party, Circa 1961-1963 (Box 41, Folder 49)
  - American Negro Conference on Africa, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 50)
  - American Newspaper Guild, 1951-1954 (Box 41, Folder 51)
  - American Parents Committee, Apr 1959 (Box 41, Folder 52)
  - American Peace Crusade, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 53)
  - American Public Relations Forum, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 54)
  - American Religious Town Hall Meeting (TV show), Oct 1958 (Box 41, Folder 55)
  - American Society for Industrial Security, circa 1957-1959 (Box 41, Folder 56)
  - American Veterans Committee [Julien H. Franklin, Kenneth M. Birkhead], 1947-1960 (Box 41, Folder 57)
  - American Veterans of the Elbe Meeting, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 58)
  - American Veterans of World War II (AMVETS), May 1957 (Box 41, Folder 59)
  - American Writers Association [The American Writer], Jan 1947 (Box 41, Folder 60)
  - Americans for Constitutional Action, circa 1957-1963 (Box 41, Folder 61)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1949-1965 (Box 41, Folder 62)
  - Americans for National Security, 1964, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 63)
  - Americans Underground [Valley Forge, Pennsylvania], circa 1955 (Box 41, Folder 64)
  - AMTORG [Soviet Trading Company], 1930, 1952, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 65)
  - Anti-anti-communists [Right Wing], circa 1961-1963 (Box 41, Folder 66)
  - Anti-Communist Liason (Newsletter) [Includes Anti-Defamation League], Circa 1962-1965 (Box 41, Folder 67)
  - Anti-Communist Organizations [Churches Against Communism, California League of Christian Parents], 1964 (Box 41, Folder 68)
  - Anti-Defamation League, circa 1947-1965 (Box 41, Folder 69)
  - Appeasers and Appeasement, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 70)
  - Area Redevelopment Legislation, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 71)
  - Arkansas Legislative Council (Report From Hearing Before the Special Education Committee), Dec 1958 (Box 41, Folder 72)
  - Arms of Friendship, 1958-1959 (Box 41, Folder 73)
  - Artists' Committee to Free Siquieros [Alexander Calder, Ben Shahn], 1962 (Box 41, Folder 74)
  - Artists Letter Fund [Petition for Disarmament in New York Times], Jun 1962 (Box 41, Folder 75)
  - Army, Department of [Organizational Chart], 1957 (Box 41, Folder 76)
  - Artists Protest [Petition in New York Times], Jan 27, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 77)
  - Assembly of Unrepresented People, Jul 1965-Aug 1965 (Box 41, Folder 78)
  - Atlantic Union, 1955-1963 (Box 41, Folder 79)
  - Association for Family Living, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 80)
  - (International) Atomic Energy Agency, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 81)
  - The Attorney General's List of Subversive Organizations, 1948-1964 (Box 41, Folder 82)
  - Authors League of America [Radio Writer's Guild], 1952-1957 (Box 41, Folder 83)
  - Bandung Conference, 1955-1961 (Box 41, Folder 84)
  - Baptist Adults Study Course [Review of "Understanding the Communist Challenge"], May 19, 1964 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Baptist World Alliance, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Bilderberg Group (Bilderbergers) [1957 St. Simon Island Conference], 1957-1964 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Bill of Rights Conference [July 16-17, 1949], Jul 1949 (Box 42, Folder 4)